Objective

I've spent much of my professional life working as a big-mountain guide, helping people summit the highest peaks on Earth, and later running one of the largest and most well-renowned guide services in the world. I'm excited to bring my leadership and project management experience to a team in a technical coding role. I cut my teeth designing, developing and deploying several projects allowing for the improvement and automation of processes across the outdoor industry. I'm excited to grow my skills through new opportunities and bring my proven and innovative work-ethic to a new team.

Profile

Proven leadership experience as Director of Operations with years of success overseeing the operations and staff of a mid-sized company, managing both day-to-day operations and long-term growth through data-driven metrics. Previous leadership experience on Mt Everest and in other outdoor industry sectors. Web Development education and experience through University of Washington.

Skills

- Leadership Proven record of effective leadership of a large and diverse staff.
- Process Development and Automation Experience implementing processes increasing productivity and satisfaction.
- Project Management Confident lead on getting projects across the finish line.
- · Programming Advanced knowledge of HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Node, and other web-based programming languages

Experience

University of Washington Coding Bootcamp/Web Development Bootcamp

Oct 2022-May 2023

- Attend over 200 hours of lecture teaching the fundamentals of web development.
- Execute a weekly project creating a functional and useable product deployed to the web
- Gain practical familiarity and use of HTML, CSS, JS.
- Practice and deploy using browser-based technologies such as Bootstrap, React, and Jquery.
- Obtain working knowledge of database management using MySQL and MongoDB.
- Gain skills in server-side development and deployment/delivery.
- Utilize sensible and usable API design.

International Mountain Guides/Director of Operations

January 2021-Present

- Run daily operations and manage a multi-leveled and diverse staff.
- Oversaw growth of 33% in 2021.
- Conduct hiring, training, performance targets and evaluation, and growth opportunities for a large (40+) staff.
- Implement and develop a pay structure designed for results-oriented work and professional development, resulting in a measured increase of workplace satisfaction.
- Implement a multi-platform customer registration system, detailed below.
- Lead company in overhauling our back-end email system, leading to a higher degree of security and allowing for the implementation of a CRM system.
- · Lead a well-rounded team through quantitative performance feedback and outlining clear expectations of work duties.
- Assist employees with real-time complex decision-making in high-risk environments.
- Manage an administrative team collecting sensitive information and oversee dissemination to staff.
- Develop and implement Covid-19 policies while working closely with governmental agencies, physicians, and private industry.
- Work closely with governmental agencies in operating within permit boundaries while still maximizing performance and financial gains.
- Create and execute marketing strategy and content based on user telemetry.

International Mountain Guides/Senior Supervising Guide, Everest Exped. Team Leader

June 2016-January 2021

- Oversee a small-to-medium-sized staff (2-10) in high-risk scenarios.
- Manage the risk, expectations, and well-being of staff and clientele in hyper objective-based climbing guiding.
- Balance client-facing and staff-facing communication when implementing strategy.
- Assist in high-hazard rescue when required.
- Led over 50 successful summits of peaks around the world, including Mt Rainier, Aconcagua, and Lhotse, among others.

Other Leadership Experience

Crystal Mountain Ski Patrol/Shift Supervisor/ June 2014-January 2019

AIARE/Avalanche Education Course Leader/ November 2017-Present

Projects

Cocktail Generator

- Developed a cocktail generator on a 3 person team using Javascript, HTML, and Bulma.
- Managed deployment of code via github

Client Registration System

- Developed and implemented a multi-platform customer registration system, using AirTable, Docusign and Zapier.
- Implemented code executing a live response view for clientele showing live availability.
- Managed team in build and deployment.

Explosives Data Collection System

- Developed and implemented a collaborative system tracking the usage of explosive ordinance across a 30-person team.
- Managed local storage of CSV and Excel file storage on local system.

Education

University of Washington/Web Development Bootcamp

University of Puget Sound/BS Chemistry

May 2023 Seattle, WA

May 2012 Tacoma, WA